# JOHN IFEMEZUO

UI/UX DESIGNER & FRONT END DEVELOPER



#### CONTACT

(Address) Anambra State, Nigeria (Phone) (+234) 706 0696 371 (Email) Ifemezuojohn@gmail.com (Porfolio) <a href="www.johnifemezuo.vercel.app">www.johnifemezuo.vercel.app</a> (Linkedin) <a href="www.linkedin.com/in/john-ifemezuo">www.linkedin.com/in/john-ifemezuo</a>

## SKILLS

HARD SKILLS: User Research, User Testing, Wireframing, Usability Testing, Prototyping, Coding

TECHNICQUE: Debugging, Interaction Design, User Testing

LANGUAGES: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Tailwind CSS

TOOLS& FRAMEWORKS: Figma, Adobe XD, Figjam, Adobe Photoshop, React, Nextjs

# PROFILE

UI/UX Designer and experienced developer with over 5 years of experience in creating user-friendly and accessible interfaces for complex systems and software. Skilled in user interface design and frontend development and prototyping using tools such as Figma, and Adobe XD. Designed and developed web and mobile applications for various clients and projects, increasing user engagement and satisfaction by 40%.



0

0

# WORK EXPERIENCE

#### VENTLIO (AWKA, ANAMBRA STATE, NIGERIA)

A software company that offer quality SaaS software applications to businesses with 100+ paying businesses .

#### LEAD PRODUCT DESIGNER

05/2022 To Present

- Overhauled the website design, layout and overall user experience (UX) of the company products leading to a 45% of retention time.
- Designed wireframes, re-usable component and high fidelity mockups of different products while assisting the front end developers with its implementation, leading to a faster development time.
- Introduced to the team ways to solve user centered design solution that facilitates sales and improve users experiences up to 70%.
- Conducted research on competitors to recommend solutions that helped in improving products to stand out benefiting 100+ of users.
- Led the front end developing team to ensure the successful implementation of UI designs, providing guidance and support throughout the development process.

#### **ZIGAH** (LAGOS, NIGERIA)

A Fintech company that offers cross border payment solutions to everyone.

#### FRONT END ENGINEER | DESIGNER

04/2022 to 04/2024

- Developed responsive and user-friendly web application systems of the company ranging from user dashboard to admin dashboard to ensuring cross-browser compatibility and optimal performance Leading to fast loading time high click through rate to about 50%.
- Developed Re-usable components using React and TailwindCss, boosting capability and reusability by 75%.

o

0

- Worked closely with back-end developers to integrate front-end components with server-side logic, ensuring smooth data flow and functionality.
- Designed email marketing template for the marketing team to use, resulting to over 50+ user sign ups a week.

## OSMAXIN (AWKA, NIGERIA)

Software Development Agency.

#### FRONT END ENGINEER & UI/UX DESIGNER

01/2020 to present

- Planned, designed and implement great user experience solution for client projects through mobile prototype, website and software development.
- Prioritize onboarding and briefs with client to understand project requirements leading to creating a great product that serves both users needs and client goals.
- Joined the development team in implementing the design layouts using Nextjs and Reactjs and integration of the APIs. Leading to faster development duration of up to 80%.
- Spearheaded application design sessions with 50+ client teams while leading the product and marketing teams to redesign the mobile onboarding process, improving retention and UX by 20%.



0

# EDUCATION

LANGUAGE

FEDERAL POLYTECHNIC, OKO, NIGERIA

HIGHER NATIONAL DIPLOMA | COMPUTER SCIENCE

2019 - 2023

English

• Pigin